Real Talk Radio that Captures Men's Hearts, Luda's Ten
남심저격 리얼 토크 라디오 루다의 텐
Starting at 10 PM with today's headlines.
밤 10시 오늘의 헤드라인으로 시작합니다.
Sound of Ten
사운드 오브 텐
9, 8, 7, 6, 5, 4, 3, 2, 1
9, 8, 7, 6, 5, 4, 3, 2, 1
Breaking News
속보
The Asian Games medal harvest has officially begun.
아시안게임 메달 수확이 본격적으로 시작됐다.
Fighting, Team Korea
대한민국 선수들 파이팅
Hello
안녕하십니까
Monday, September 25, 2023, Bae Sung-jae's Ten
2023년 9월 25일 월요일 배성재의 텐
In place of DJ Bae Sung-jae, who has stepped aside for the Hangzhou Asian Games broadcast,
항저우 아시안게임 중계를 위해 자리를 비운 배성재 DJ를 대신해서
I, Luda, will be hosting this week's Luda's Ten. Nice to meet you.
이번주 루다의 텐을 진행하게 된 루다입니다. 반갑습니다.
The first song was 'Fighting' by 'Bo Suk Soon'.
첫 곡은 '부석순'의 '파이팅해야지'였고요.
The headline announcing 10 o'clock is
10시를 알려드리는 헤드라인은
The Asian Games medal harvest has officially begun.
아시안 게임 메달 수확이 본격적으로 시작됐다.
Fighting, Team Korea.
대한민국 선수들 파이팅이었습니다.
The Hangzhou Asian Games are now in their second day.
항저우 아시안 게임이 오늘로써 이틀째인데요.
Our athletes have been doing great since the first day.
첫날부터 우리 선수들의 활약이 대단하다고 합니다.
Taekwondo Poomsae, Modern Pentathlon, Fencing, Swimming, Judo, etc.
태권도 품세, 근대 오종, 펜싱, 수영, 유도 등
Medals are coming out in various events.
다양한 종목에서 메달이 나오고 있거든요.
And in the swimming event that Bae Sung-jae is broadcasting, the men's freestyle 50m,
그리고 배디가 중계하는 수영, 남자 자유형 50m에서도
Ji Yoo-chan won a gold medal, so currently, South Korea has 10 gold medals,
지유찬 선수가 금메달을 따면서 현재 대한민국은 금메달 10개
10 silver medals, and 13 bronze medals,
은메달 10개, 동메달은 13개
A total of 30 medals.
총 30개의 메달을 땄고요.
And we are still on the hunt for more medals.
지금도 계속 메달 사냥에 나서고 있습니다.
Regardless of the color of the medal, for those who have run for the Asian Games,
메달 색과 상관없이 아시안게임을 위해 달려온
Thank you very much to the Korean national team.
대한민국 선수단 여러분 수고 많으시고요.
Even if you didn't win a medal, thank you to all the athletes who have done their best
메달을 못 땄더라도 국가대표가 되어 최선을 다해
As national representatives and are still running in the games.
경기를 뛰어 주시고 계신 선수분들께 모두 감사드립니다.
I can't watch every game, but I'm cheering from afar,
경기를 일일이 챙겨보지 못하지만 멀리서 응원하고 있으니까
Fighting, Team Korea.
대한민국 선수분들 파이팅이시고요.
Fighting to the broadcast team, including DJ Bae Sung-jae, who is delivering news about our athletes,
우리 선수들 소식을 전해주고 계신 배성재 DJ를 비롯한
And to the broadcast team.
중계진 분들도 파이팅입니다.
Please take care of Hangzhou, I'll take care of here.
여기는 제가 지킬 테니 항저우를 지켜주세요.
I’m not sure if I should read this on air today,
오늘은 이렇게 읽어도 되는지 모르겠지만
But this is the script,
이게 대본이니까
With Jung Yong-guk, a gagman who is living a wrong life,
잘못된 인생을 살고 있는 듣보 개그맨 정영국 씨와
We will be doing the counseling corner, 'Go All Out Spicy Counseling Center'.
고민 상담 코너, '막 나가는 용한상담소' 함께 할게요.
Instead of comfort and warm advice, harsh words, disses, and
위로와 따뜻한 조언 대신 막말과 쎈말, 디스가 오고 가는
Realistic counseling is what they say.
현실적인 상담이라고 하는데요.
I wonder if it will go well with my cynical self, or not.
냉소적인 저와 잘 맞을지 아님 네.
We'll check in the corner later.
잠시 후 코너에서 확인해 보겠고요.
If you want to receive realistic and direct counseling from Mr. Jung Yong-guk,
정용국 씨의 현실적이고 직설적인 상담을 받고 싶으신 분들
Please send your concerns via short text for 50 won, long text for 100 won to #1077.
#1077 짧은 문자 50원 긴 문자 100원으로 고민 사연 보내주세요.
If you want to listen while watching the live broadcast,
생방송을 보면서 듣고 싶으신 분들은
You can see Gorilla...
고릴라나 보...
You can enter through Gorilla's Visible Radio or Kakao TV
고릴라 보이는 라디오나 카카오티비의 이 라디오의 주인
By searching for Bae Sung-jae.
배성재를 검색하시고 들어오시고요.
YouTube... Uh, sorry.
유튜브... 응 죄송해요.
It is also broadcast live on the YouTube Erao channel.
유튜브 에라오 채널에서도 생중계됩니다.
Before the main corner, there is a text introduction corner
본 코너 전에 문자 소개 코너
Called Freestyle Confessions.
프리선언이 있으니까요.
If you want to talk to me, Luda,
저 루다한테 말 걸고 싶으신 분들
Please feel free to send daily texts.
일상 문자도 편하게 보내주세요.
Yes. If you send any message freely, I will introduce it in
네. 어떤 말이든 자유롭게 보내주시면 소개해드리는
The text introduction corner, Freestyle Confessions.
문자 소개 코너 프리선언.
'Now More Warring' sent this.
'이제 더 워잉' 님께서 보내주셨는데요.
'Who is Bae Sung-jae?'
'배성재가 누군데요?'
You sent this, but uh, wait a minute.
라고 보내주셨는데 어 잠시만요.
I'll be back after listening to the ads. Freestyle Confessions.
광고 듣고 와서 할게요. 프리선언은.
Any comments you send will be introduced in the text introduction corner, Freestyle Confessions.
어떤 말이든 자유롭게 보내주시면 소개해드리는 문자 소개 코너 프리선언.
I just saw a comment.
방금 댓글을 보니까요.
Subin, who was here last time, also skipped the ads like I did.
그 저번에 오셨던 수빈 언니도 저렇게 저처럼 광고를 스킵하셨다고 하시더라고요.
I apologize to the advertisers.
광고주님들 죄송합니다.
Yes, 4210 sent this.
네. 4210님께서 보내주셨는데요.
"Luda, is this your first time as a radio DJ?"
'루다 님 라디오 DJ는 처음인 걸로 아는데 맞나요? '
"I'm curious about your feelings about being the first radio DJ on Baeten."
'하필 배텐에서 첫 라디오 DJ를 맡게 된 소감이 어떤지 궁금합니다.'
Actually, it's my first time as a DJ, so I'm very nervous.
사실 지금 첫 DJ라 많이 떨립니다.
I look forward to your kind cooperation, Baeten listeners.
베텐러 여러분 잘 부탁드려요.
"Bae Sung-jae, don't come" sent "WJSN Subin was the first substitute DJ on Baeten. Did you get any tips?"
'배성재 오지마'님께서 '우주소녀 수빈님이 배탠 대타DJ로 먼저 다녀갔는데요. 혹시 팁 같은 거 전수 받았나요?'
"like 'Be careful with the Monday guest.' "
'월요일 게스트는 조심해라 이런 거요.' 라고 보내주셨는데요.
Actually, I contacted her right after she went to Baeten.
사실 언니가 베텐에 나가고 바로 제가 연락을 했었어요.
When I asked how it was, she said, "It was very draining."
어땠냐 그랬더니 '기가 많이 빨렸다' 하더라고요.
But is that the Monday guest?
근데 그게 월요일 게스트인가요?
I'm not sure.
잘 모르겠어요 저는.
5878 sent "I went to the mart on the weekend and people were busy preparing for the holiday. It was a weekend that was excited by the busy and busy atmosphere unique to the holiday."
5878 님께서 '주말에 마트 갔는데 사람들이 명절 준비로 분주하더라고요. 명절 특유의 바쁘고 분주한 분위기에 덩달아 들떴던 주말이었어요.' 라고 보내주셨어요.
And 'Park In-gyu' sent "Ludi looks relaxed. Keke."
그리고 '박인규' 님께서 '루디 뭔가 여유로워 보이네요. 크크.'
"Think back to the time when you mercilessly advised listeners during the ‘Pathetic’ segment and just relax."
''비참' 나왔을 때처럼 그냥 두드려 팬다고 생각하고 편하게 하면 됩니다.'
"There's PD Panghyun who will wear a suit and apologize to the Broadcasting Commission."
'슈트는 어차피 팡현 PD가 입는 거니까요. 크크.' 라고 보내주셨어요.
Do I look relaxed?
저 여유로워 보이나요?
I'm a robot.
세상 로봇인데요.
7938 sent "I came to pick up my daughter who is going to take her first test from tomorrow after becoming a middle school student, and I heard Luda's voice."
7938 님께서 '중학생 되고 내일부터 첫 시험을 치르는 딸 데릴러 학원 앞에 왔다가 켰는데 루다 님의 목소리가 들리네요.'
"It's cute that you're a little clumsy and stuttering. Laugh laugh."
'약간 서툴며 버벅거리는게 귀여워요. 웃음 웃음.'
"I'm listening while laughing in the car on a rainy day."
'비 오는 날 차 안에서 피식피식 웃으며 듣고 있어요.'
I don't stutter much.
저 많이 버벅거리지 않습니다.
Yes, that was Luda's Freestyle Confessions.
네. 이상 루다의 프리선언이었습니다.
We will listen to your concerns, but please bear with the emotional wounds that you may experience during the consultation.
여러분의 고민을 들어는 드릴 테니 상담 중 겪게 될 마음의 상처는 알아서 잘견뎌내십시오.
A very spicy counseling center where harsh words and witty remarks fly back and forth. 'Jung Yong-guk's 'Go All Out Spicy Counseling Center'.
막말과 쎈말을 오가는 아주 독한 상담소. '정용국'의 '막 나가는 용한 상담소'.
A strange man who gets a question bombing every time a special DJ comes.
스페셜 DJ들이 올 때마다 질문 폭격을 받는 이상한 남자.
Welcome, unheard-of comedian Jung Yong-guk.
듣보 개그맨 정용국 씨 어서 오세요.
Nice to meet you. I'm the unheard-of comedian, Jung Yong-guk.
반갑습니다. 듣보 개그맨 정용국입니다.
We've met before, right?
네. 저희 뵀었잖아요. 그죠?
Really?
그래요?
Yes. Don't you remember?
네. 기억 안나세요?
Where did we meet?
어디서 뵀어요?
During Baeten?
배텐 때?
Yes
네
I didn't see you.
안 봤어요?
Really?
그래요?
Yes.
네.
You said you would give me tripe then.
그때 저한테 곱창 주신다고.
Me?
제가요?
Yes. I don't remember well, but I remember the tripe because you said you would give me a good deal on tripe.
네. 곱창 싸게 해 주신다고 그러셨던 게 저도 잘 기억이 안 나는데 곱창이 기억이 남아서.
There's no one but me for tripe.
곱창은 저밖에 없는데.
Yes, you didn't give me tripe. But.
네. 곱창 안 주셨잖아요. 근데.
Didn't you come?
안 오시지 않았나?
Yes, I didn't go.
네. 안 갔어요.
What's that?
뭐야 그게?
I didn't go, but I didn't see you.
안 갔는데 안 봤었어요.
Yes, that's it.
네. 그런 거네요.
Yes.
네.
Ah, we met.
아. 뵀구나.
Yes, we've met. Right, everyone? Yes, we've met.
네. 뵌 적 있습니다. 맞죠 여러분? 네. 봤습니다.
I see. I didn't know. As people age, their memory tends to decline.
그렇군요. 몰랐습니다. 나이가 들면 기억이 잘 안 납니다.
That can happen.
그러실 수 있죠.
Can it happen?
그러실 수 있다고요?
Yes, I totally understand.
네. 완전 이해합니다.
Yes, thank you.
네. 고맙습니다.
Every time special DJs come, they say that a barrage of questions is unleashed on Mr. Jung Yong-guk.
네. 스페셜 DJ들이 올 때마다 정용국 님께 질문 폭격이 펼쳐진다고 하던데.
What kind of questions do you get?
어떤 질문들을 받으시나요?
What do you do? How did you get here? Something like that.
뭐 하는 사람이냐? 여긴 어떻게 왔냐? 뭐 이런 느낌으로.
How did you get in? Like that.
어떻게 들어왔냐? 이런.
Yes, Subin was like that last time. Yes, to me. Who is this person? What is this? Kind of like that.
네. 그때 수빈 씨도 그랬어요. 네. 저한테. 이 사람은 뭐지? 이게 뭐야? 약간 이런 느낌으로.
At that time, I said I had been doing it for 7 years. "Eh? You’ve been doing it for that long?" So I heard a lot of strange stories.
그때는 제가 7년 했다고 그러니까. 에? 그렇게 오래 했다고요? 그래서 굉장히 뭐 이상한 얘기 많이 들었습니다.
Then, how do I look to you?
그럼 혹시 저는 뭐 하는 사람처럼 보이시는지.
Aren't you a girl group?
아이 걸그룹 아니겠습니까?
Really? Oh, thank you.
아 정말요? 아 감사합니다.
But you look really pale in person.
근데 실제로 보니까 굉장히 하얗네요.
There's a lot of lighting here.
여기가 조명이 되게 많네요.
Don't I have lighting? I should have lighting too, right?
난 조명이 없나 그러면? 나도 조명 있을 거 아니야. 그쵸?
It seems like there's no lighting there.
거기가 조명이 없는 거 같아요.
Do you look at people without saying anything?
그렇게 말을 안 하고 쳐다보고 있다고 사람을?
It seems like the lighting doesn't go well there.
거기 조명이 잘 안 가는 거 같아요.
Your face is really small.
얼굴 진짜 작고.
Oh, thank you.
아 감사합니다.
You're really pretty.
되게 예쁘네요.
'I would remember you if I saw you, so why can't I remember?
내가 근데 봤던 걸 기억을 못 하지. 무조건 기억하는데 그러면.
I'm upset. A little. My heart hurts.
서운하네요. 조금. 마음이 아파요.
'Don't speak so confidently when you don't even come to our store
안 오고 그렇게 크게 얘기해서 가세요.
Yes, I understand.
네. 알겠습니다.
Yes.
네.
Eun Jung Hoon sent 'I expected it, but it's really awkward. Kekekeke' Are we not awkward? Aren't we okay?
은정훈 님께서 '와 예상은 했지만 진짜 어색하다. 크크크크' 라고 보내주셨는데 저희 안 어색하지 않나요? 저희 괜찮지 않나요?
This person is just talking.
아 이분은 그냥 하는 말입니다.
Oh, really?
아 그래요?
Yes, you don't have to worry at all.
네. 전혀 신경 안쓰셔도 돼요.
We're not awkward.
저희 안 어색해요.
Yes, it's the Asian Games season now.
네. 지금 아시안게임 시즌이잖아요.
Are you watching any games?
혹시 경기 보고 계시는 거 있나요?
I saw earlier in the elevator that DJ Bae Sung-jae is currently broadcasting swimming
좀 전에 엘리베이터에서 봤더니 배성재 DJ가 지금 수영 중계하고 있더라고요.
Yes, that's right.
네. 맞아요.
Yes, I watch it sometimes.
네. 가끔 보고 있습니다.
Sometimes.
가끔.
Yes, I watch soccer.
네. 축구는 챙겨 보고 있는데.
Soccer.
축구.
Yes, because Bae Di is broadcasting again.
네. 배디가 또 중계를 하니까.
Korea is a soccer nation after all. Probably. Koreans really like soccer.
한국은 역시 축구의 민족이죠. 아무래도. 한국인들이 축구를 되게 많이 좋아하잖아요.
Is that so?
그런가요?
Yes, that's right.
그렇죠.
Yes, there's a story for Jung Yong Guk.
네. 정용국 씨 앞으로 온 사연이 있네요.
Yes, tell me.
네. 얘기하십시오.
Ha Jungsuk sent 'I'm looking forward to the combination of cynical Luda and Jung Yong Guk.'
하중수 님께서 '냉소적인 루다 님과 정용국 님의 조합이 기대 중이에요.' 라고.
I can't figure out the character right now.
저는 지금 캐릭터 파악이 아예 안 되고 있습니다.
My character analysis?
저의 캐릭터 파악이요?
Yes.
네.
Hehe.
허허.
Yes, I have no idea at all.
네. 아예 감이 안 잡혀요.
In the middle of the conversation.
중간에 이제 얘기를 하면서.
I think I need to understand your personality to figure out what kind of talk I can have with you.
어떤 성향인지 들어봐야 어떤 토크를 할지 생각을 해야 될 것 같습니다.
'5990' sent 'What is Luda's worry?' How about counseling Jung Yong Guk before the tasting?'
'5990'님께서 '루다의 고민은 뭔가요?' 맛보기로 시작하기 전에 정용국 님께 고민 상담을 해보면 어떨까요?'
Do you have any worries? No, right?
혹시 고민이 있습니까? 없죠?
I do have one big worry in my life.
저 진짜 일생일대에 고민이 하나 있긴 있어요.
That sigh was real.
앞에 그 한숨이 찐이었습니다.
Yes, what is it?
네. 뭡니까?
I want to cut my hair.
저 머리를 자르고 싶은데.
I don't know much about hair.
저는 머리 쪽은 잘 몰라서.
!!!!!!!!!
허억
Do you react like that?
그런 반응이 나온다고?
Hair
헤어가
That's the only thing I don't know.
제가 제일 모르는 게 딱 그거 하나 있는데.
I don't know about hair.
헤어는 모릅니다.
Oh, then let's move on.
아잇. 그럼 넘어가 보도록 하겠습니다.
Then.
그러면.
What is this?
뭐야 이게.
This is enough for the preview talk.
맛보기 토크는 이 정도로.
I was surprised.
깜짝 놀라버렸네요.
Let's go into the home corner.
홈코너 들어가 보도록 하겠습니다.
'Go All Out Spicy Counseling Center' is receiving your concerns.
'막 나가는 용한 상담소'는 여러분의 고민을 받고 있습니다.
Please send your concerns to #1077, short text for 50 won, long text for 100 won, free for Gorilla or mobile messenger, or post your concerns on the Monday board.
고민은 #1077 짧은 문자 50원 긴 문자 100원 무료인 고릴라나 모바일 메신저로 보내시거나 월요일 게시판에 고민 사연을 올려주세요.
For all the people introduced, what is the gift 'Sixpan exchange coupon'?
소개된 모든 분들께, 선물 '식스팬 교환권'이 뭐죠?
Sixpack.
식스팩.
We give you a 'Sixpack exchange coupon'.
'식스팩 교환권'을 드립니다.
Then, shall we start with the corner inside the corner that introduces the story of 1 day 1 year of the 'Go All Out Spicy Counseling Center'?
그럼 막 나가는 용안 상담소 1일 1년의 사연을 소개하는 코너 속의 코너부터 시작해볼까요?
Jung Yong-guk's Love Theory.
정용국의 연애학개론.
There's a man who confessed to me a year ago.
1년 전 저한테 고백했던 남자분이 있는데요.
I refused and we're getting along well as colleagues.
제가 거절해서 동료로 잘 지내고 있어요.
A female employee who joined the company recently asked me to push that man well.
얼마 전에 입사한 여직원이 저한테 그 남자분과 잘 되게 밀어달래요.
It's a bit uncomfortable situation, isn't it?
좀 불편한 상황이잖아요.
Should I pretend not to know and let it go? Or should I just create an opportunity for them to be together?"
알아서 하라고 모른 척할까요? 그냥 슬쩍 자리를 한번 만들어주는 게 나을까요?
This is the story of a woman from 8024.
8024 여자분의 사연입니다.
There's a man who confessed a year ago, and she refused, and a female employee who joined the company recently asked me to help him do well.
1년 전 고백했던 남자분이 있는데 자기가 거절을 했고 얼마 전에 입사한 여직원이 그 남자분과 잘 되게 해달라고 나한테 도움을 요청했다.
This is the story, but I've done a lot anyway.
이런 사연인데 저는 뭐 어차피 많이 해봤으니까.
Confession?
고백을요?
The story.
사연을.
Oh, surprise.
아 깜짝이야.
I'm old doesn't mean I've done a lot.
나이 많다고 다 많이 해본건 아니에요.
I thought you were a pro confessor.
프로 고백러 인줄 알았습니다.
So, how do you see it? Please tell me.
자 보기 어떻습니까? 얘기해 주십시오.
I don't think you'd be curious about my story.
제 이야기는 별로 궁금해할 것같지 않고.
Yeah
응
What should she do?
어떻게 해야 됩니까?
If it were me, I would just make a place once.
저라면 그냥 자리 한번 만들어 줄 것 같아요.
Is that so?
아 그래요?
Yes.
네.
This person confessed a year ago, and it seems a bit awkward for her, but does that matter?
이분은 1년 전에 고백했던 게 자기한테 약간 좀 껄끄러운 상황인 것 같은데 그런 거 상관없습니까?
I heard that the sender didn't confess, but refused.
뭐 자기가 제가 이게 사연자분이 고백한 게 아니고 거절하셨다면서요.
By introducing another person like this, 'I have no interest in you at all and anyway, I was asked to help, so there's nothing that can't be done' I think I'll do it.
이렇게 또 다른 분을 소개해 줌으로써 '나는 너에게 완벽히 관심이 없고 어쨌든 뭐 도와달라는 부탁을 받았으니 뭐 안 될 게 없지' 하고 저는 해드릴 것 같거든요.
Oh, looking at your face, it seems like you've been rejected a lot.
어. 얼굴 보니까 거절 많이 해보신 것 같은데.
It was a life of rejection.
거절의 삶이었습니다.
Yes, I think I have a similar idea.
네. 저도 뭐 비슷한 생각인 것 같은데.
You don't have to worry at all.
전혀 뭐 신경 안 쓰셔도 될 것 같고.
Even if you make a place once, there won't be a big situation.
자리 한번 마련해 줘도 큰 상황은 없을 것 같다.
But the point here is, wasn't there a man who confessed a year ago?
근데 여기 포인트가 뭐냐면 1년 전에 고백했던 남자가 있지 않습니까?
Why did I tell you not to worry about this person? This person may not know that he confessed.
이분을 왜 신경을 제가 쓰지 말라 그랬냐면 이분은 본인이 고백했는지도 모를 겁니다.
Hmm. Is it your experience?
음. 경험이신가요?
Don't keep pushing that way.
자꾸 그쪽을 몰지 마시고.
No. A year is a very long time, right?
아니. 1년이면 굉장히 긴 시간이죠?
That's right.
그렇죠.
There must be a lot of employees in the company, right?
회사에 엄청 많은 직원이 있겠죠?
Did he confess to only one woman?
과연 이 여자분 한 명한테만 고백을 했을까요?
Is it that bad? Suddenly?
그렇게 최악이라고요? 갑자기?
It's not the worst. Honestly, it's not a good situation.
최악까진 아닌데. 뭐 솔직히 좋은 상황은 아니죠.
So now this woman may remember, but.
그래서 이제 그 여자분은 이제 기억을 하고 있을지 모르겠지만.
Since the man who failed to confess his love
그 남자분이 이 여자분한테 고백을 까였다 그래서.
so he could meet another girl,
다른 여자분을 안 만난 것도 아닐 수도 있고.
he could confess to another girl,
다른 분한테 고백을 안 한 걸 수도 있기 때문에.
You don't have to worry about that.
그거는 이제 본인이 뭐 신경 안 쓰셔도 되고요.
Oh, it's a bit uncomfortable, but you don't need to think about it at all.
아 좀 불편한데 이거는 뭐 전혀 생각하실 필요가 없다.
That's right.
그렇습니다.
Then just tell the female employee who ‘asked you to make this opportunity’ to ‘wait a little bit’.
그러면은 그냥 이 자리를 만들어 달라고 한 여직원분께 조금만 기다려봐라.
Yes.
네.
He's going to confess.
고백을 할 것이다.
No, that's not it.
아 그건 아니에요.
If you look at the food pyramid, it's like a character pyramid.
이제 그 먹이 피라미드 비슷하게 인물 피라미드를 보면.
Now this story teller is at the top.
이제 이 사연자분이 제일 위에 있고.
And now the man is in the middle.
그리고 이제 남자분이 중간에 있고.
The new employee who just came in hasn't been there for long, but she's already trying to date.
이제 들어온 신입사원은 들어온 지 얼마 안 됐는데 벌써부터 연애를 하려고 그러네요.
So, the company runs well with this structure, really.
그래서 이런 구도로 회사 잘 돌아간다 진짜.
They say they do something.
뭐 한다고 하는데.
Isn't it that everything works out just because they introduce it?
이게 소개시켜준다 그래서 다 되는 건 아니지 않습니까?
That's right.
그렇죠.
People think it will go well in the future when they go on a blind date.
사람들이 소개팅 나간다고 하면 앞으로 이제 잘 될 거라고 생각을 하는데.
First of all, a blind date is just a place someone has prepared.
일단 소개팅은 그냥 누가 마련해 준 자리고.
That's right.
그렇죠.
Usually, the probability of failure is higher.
그게 거의 보통 파토널 확률이 더 많거든요.
Rather than the probability of success.
어 잘 될 확률보다.
That's right.
그렇죠.
Of course.
당연하죠.
Isn't it?
그렇지 않습니까?
Because you have a lot of experience.
역시 경험이 많으시니까.
What do you think I do for a living right now?
나 뭐 하는 사람인 줄 알고 있는 거야 지금.
I don't know.
모르겠어요.
So, you can just do it.
그래서 그냥 해 주셔도 되고.
Yes.
네.
The bad thing is that even if the two of them do well, I don't think there will be an expression of gratitude.
안 좋은 건 뭐냐면 둘이 설사 잘 된다 한들 고마움의 표현은 없을 것 같습니다.
I don't think she's looking for the expression of gratitude.
고마움의 표현을 받고 싶어 하는 거는 아닐 테니까요.
But if the person who sent the story is uncomfortable, it seems right not to do it.
근데 만약에 사연자분께서 불편하면 안 하시는 게 맞는 것 같기도 하고.
Is that so? I don't think it will be uncomfortable.
아 그래요? 불편하지 않을 것 같아요.
I think so too.
저도 그렇게 생각합니다.
Yes.
네.
This person seems to have sent a concern because of that.
이분이 이제 그렇게 그것 때문에 고민을 보내주신 것 같은데.
Just do whatever you want.
그냥 뭐 하고 싶은 대로 하는 거지 뭐.
That's right. That's right.
그렇죠. 그렇죠.
You do whatever you want.
하고 싶은 대로 하는 거죠.
And then it goes really well.
그리고 이제 너무 잘 된다.
It's a bit annoying to see. Even if it's not jealousy.
보기 좀 짜증난다. 질투까지는 아니어도.
Throw a word when it's going well later.
나중에 잘 되고 있을 때 한 마디 던지세요.
He's the one I rejected.
내가 깠던 애야.
Why?
왜?
That's a bit.
그거는 조금.
No, it can be green with envy if it goes well.
아니 잘 되면 배 아플 수 있잖아요.
Why are you upset about it?
아니 까놓고 왜 배가 아파요.
Most people are like that.
보통 사람이 다 그렇습니다.
Usually, when it goes well, they come to me and buy me a meal or a cup of coffee. If they just think they're doing well, you can throw it in the middle.
보통 잘 되면 나한테 와서 무슨 밥 한 끼를 산다든가  무슨 커피 한 잔 준다든가 이런 게 있어야 되는데 그냥 둘이 잘 된 줄 알고 이러고 있으면 중간에 한 번 툭 던지면 됩니다.
He confessed to me.
나한테 고백했었지.
You're a scary person.
무서우신 분이네요.
Are you not adapted to this culture?
이런 문화 적응이 안 됩니까?
Yes.
네.
That's right. I haven't even started yet
그래요. 시작도 안했는데
While summarizing the story, let's hear a word of Jung Yong-guk's love guide.
사연을 정리하면서 정용국 씨의 연애 지침 한 마디 들어보도록 하겠습니다.
Jung Yong-guk's Love Theory.
정용국의 연애학개론.
You don't need to worry at all. Men tend to forget their own confessions
전혀 고백할 이런 문제가 없는 게 남자들은 본인이 고백했던 걸 잘 잊어먹습니다.
Is that something to admire?
그렇게 감탄할 얘기인가요.
I don't understand.
이해가 안 돼가지고요.
That's right.
그래요.
Yes.
네.
Usually, when a man confesses, women often feel sorry when they refuse.
여자분들은 보통 남자가 고백을 했을 때 거절을 하면 되게 미안해하는 경우가 있는데.
There's no need to feel sorry because men already know they're going to be rejected and talk, so they don't have to feel sorry.
미안해 할 필요가 없는 게 남자분들은 이미 까일 거를 알고 얘기를 하기 때문에 미안해하지 않아도 된다.
Do men confess knowing they might be rejected?
까일 거를 알고 고백을 한다고요.
That's right. To some extent.
그렇죠. 어느 정도는.
Wrong
땡
Why?
왜요.
Is it a strange story?
이상한 얘기입니까.
This is quite generalized.
이거 되게 일반화되어 있는데요.
Isn't it just Jung Yong-guk who thinks he will be rejected and confesses?
정용국 님께서만 까일 거를 생각하시고 고백하는 거 아닐까요.
I'm the only one who gets rejected.
나만 까인다고.
Isn't it?
그러면 아닐까요?
Usually, they go with the probability of being rejected.
보통 근데 까일 확률을 갖고 가요.
Do you go? I guess so.
갖고 가요? 그러긴 하겠죠.
Really.
진짜예요.
I can't figure out your character right now.
캐릭터 파악이 안 돼가지고지금 제가.
It's hard.
어렵네요.
Is it hard?
어렵다고요.
Yes.
네.
Then let's go for a general story first.
일단 그럼 일반 사연 한번 가보시죠.
Story number one.
1번 사연.
Why?
왜요?
I have story number one.
제가 1번 사연이.
Yes.
네.
I don't have it.
없는데요.
General story.
일반 사연.
Is there no next story?
그 다음 사연 없나요.
Ah, here it is.
아, 여기 있습니다.
Yes.
네.
I'm out of my mind right now.
내가 지금 정신이 없어가지고.
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
Luda's Ten with special DJ Luda.
스페셜 dj 루다와 함께하는 루다의 텐.
The door to the second part has opened.
2부의 문 열었고요.
We are doing a counseling corner 'Go All Out Spicy Counseling Center' with the wrong man, Jung Yong-guk.
잘못된 남자 정용국 씨와 함께 고민 상담 코너 '막 나가는 용한 상담소' 하고 있습니다.
Shall we meet your worries right away?
여러분의 고민 바로 만나볼까요.
After deliberation, Mr. Jung Yong-guk gives a strong wake-up call to the person in distress, helping them regain their senses and solve their problems.
고민 후에는 '정용국' 씨가 '고민자' 정신을 차리게 하고 고민을 해결 해 갈 수 있도록 강한 일침을 쏴 드립니다.
You can do it.
하시면 됩니다.
It's a story sent by a man named 'Kang Jun-seo'.
'강준서' 남자분께서 보내주신 사연 인데요.
I don't like anything much, and even if I do, I easily get bored.
저는 좋아하는 것도 별로 없고 뭘 좋아 하더라도 쉽게 실증이 나요.
So I can't work for a long time.
그래서 일을 오래 못 다닙니다.
But thinking about the people I work with, I endure it for about a year to a year and a half
그래도 같이 일하는 사람들을 생각 하면 꾸역꾸역 버텨서 1년 1년 반
I do work, but I have to earn money for a lifetime.
정도 일하긴 하는데 돈은 평생 벌어야 하잖아요.
So I wonder if I can live like this, but if I get bored, I want to quit again.
그래서 이렇게 살아도 되는 걸까 싶다가도 이러다 실증 나면 또 그만두고 싶습니다.
Give me a wake-up call ㅠㅠ.
저한테 일침 좀 날려주세요 ㅠㅠ.
What do you think?
어떻게 보십니까.
You keep staring at me.
자꾸 째려봐요.
No, how do you see the story?
아니 어떻게 보냐고 사연을.
The story?
사연을요.
You have to talk, don't you?
얘기를 해줘야 될 거 아닙니까 .
I can just talk comfortably?
그냥 뭐 편하게 얘기해도 되는 거죠.
Live as you please.
마음대로 사세요.
If you don't want to do it, quit, if you want to do more, do it, you don't know if you'll die tomorrow
하다 하기 싫으면 그만두고 하고 싶으면 더 하고 내일 당장 죽을지
That's life, you have to live doing what you want. Right?
모르는 게 인생인데 하고 싶은 거 하면서 살아야지요. 그렇지요?
It seems like Pomnyun monk is here now. 'Just live as you want.'
법륜 스님 오신 것 같은데 지금. 그냥 하고 싶은 대로 살자
I think so.
제 생각 그렇습니다.
But now, Jun-seo, can you live like this?
그런데 이제 준서 씨께서는 이렇게 살아도 되는 걸까.
Especially, he wants to work, but he hasn't felt much yet
특히 자기는 일을 하고 싶지만 아직까지는 많이 못 느끼고 있는 그런 상태에서
It seems like he sent a story.
사연을 보낸 것 같아요.
I think so.
제 생각이 그렇습니다.
Work for about a year to a year and a half and then quit.
1년에서 1년 반 정도 일을 하고 그만둔다.
Why do you think so? I think it's because of unemployment benefits.
왜 그런 것 같습니까? 제가 봤을 땐 실업급여 때문에 그렇습니다.
Why are you sighing like this?
아니 왜 이렇게 한숨을 쉬세요?
Ah, it's ding-dong-dang, ah, it's ding-dong-dang, this again
아 딩동댕이에요 아 딩동댕이야 이거 또
This makes sense.
이거 일리가 있습니다.
Absolutely.
무조건이지.
It makes sense.
일리 있습니다.
Unemployment benefits make sense.
실업급여 이거 일리가 있어요 .
If you receive unemployment benefits and the money comes out, doesn't it come out 60% 70% then
실업급여를 받고 돈이 나오다가 60% 70% 나오지 않습니까 그러면
Now, if you order a little less delivery food and eat it, if the money is a little less, then
이제 배달비 좀 적은 거 좀 시켜 먹다가 돈이 이제 좀 없으면 그래
Let's work again and then work again and then when the money runs out again, unemployment benefits again
또 일하자 하고 또 일을 하고 그다음에 또 돈이 또 떨어지면 실업급여 또
And then go to another place for an interview and say, "I can't get social insurance?" then don't go.
하고 다른 데 이제 면접 보러 가서 어 사대보험 안 돼요 그럼 안 다니고.
You are at an age where you can do this now.
이렇게 할 수 있는 나이에 있는 거예요 지금.
If you don't avoid hard and difficult tasks, your age, which allows you to receive requests, makes these tasks seem less significant. As you age... I'll stop here.
자기가 가서 약간 좀 힘든 일 좀 굳은 일 뭐 마다하지 않고 하면
You are at an age where you can do more work.
어떤 일이 든 할 수 있는 그런 나이에 있다 보니까.
This doesn't seem to matter now, but as you get older.
이게 지금 대수롭지않게 보이는데 나이를 좀 먹어가면.
I will do up to here.
여기까지 하도록 하겠습니다.
For now, I will do up to here because of time and continue in the third part.
일단 시간때문에 여기까지 하고 3부에서 이어갈게요.
@We work and earn money for happiness or love, but life is not about taking a test and getting a conclusion.
@행복이나 사랑 위해 일을 하고 돈 벌지만 시험 치듯 결론 나는 인생살이 아니잖아.
@Let's not get confused about the absolute frequency, it's Bae Sung-jae's Ten, shortened to Baeten.
@우린 절대 주파수 절대로 헷갈리지 말자 파워의 편 배성재의 텐 줄여서 배텐이다.
@Women are more interested in men's stories, they know how to talk about cars and dramas.
@여자들이 오히려 더 알고 싶은 남자 얘기 자동차나 드라마 얘기 모두 다 다 할 줄 알아.
@A man's broadcast for men, so it's also for women's hearts
@남자를 위하는 남자의 방송 그러니 여자들의 마음도 다 정도
@Do something, brother, everyone, it's the first broadcast for men
@뭐라도 안 해 오빠 형님 모두 다 들어가 남자를 위한 방송 처음이야
@Men and women of all ages, if you're curious, you can come in and listen, SBS Bae Sung-jae's Ten
@남녀노소 궁금하면 들어와서 들어도 돼 SBS 배성재의 텐
It's Luda's Ten with special DJ Luda, not Bae Sung-jae.
스페셜 DJ 루다와 함께하는 배성재 아니 루다의 텐입니다.
Somehow, the third part started today.
오늘만 어쩌다 보니까 3부가 시작됐습니다.
We are doing a counseling corner 'Go All Out Spicy Counseling Center' with the wrong man, Jung Yong-guk.
잘못된 남자 정용국씨와 함께 고민상담 코너 '막 나가는 용한상담소'.
Shall we meet the next worry?
다음 고민 만나볼까요?
Let's go.
가시죠.
Mr. 'Lee Soon-bong' sent it, he's a man.
'이순봉'님께서 남자분께서 보내주셨는데요.
There is ginseng liquor at home, I drank it all secretly and filled it with plain water
집에 인삼주가 있는데요 제가 몰래 다 마시고 맹물을 채워놨는데
My wife says she wants to drink it with the family this holiday to celebrate our son's employment.
아내가 아들 취업 기념으로 이번 명절에 가족들이랑 같이 마시재요.
What should I do? Yong-guk, did you secretly drink your parents' ginseng liquor when you were young?
어찌해야 합니까? 용국씨도 어렸을 때 부모님 인삼주를
What did you do then with your friends?
친구들과 몰래 먹어 본 경험이 있으신가요? 그때 어떻게 하셨나요?
How much can you drink?
주량이 어떻게 되십니까?
It's my first time talking about my drinking capacity in public.
저는 공개적인 곳에서 주량을 얘기하는 건 또 처음인데요.
The drinking capacity is okay. It's okay.
주량은 괜찮습니다. 괜찮아요.
I can drink about a bottle and a half
저는 한 병 반 정도
I hardly drink alcohol at all.
저는 아예 술을 거의 안 마셔요.
Oh really?
오 진짜요?
Is that surprising?
네 그렇게 놀랄 일인가요?
You look like you drink a lot.
진짜 많이 잘 드실 것 같아요.
I see, I've heard that a lot.
그렇군요 그런 얘기 많이 들었습니다.
When I met senior Ji Sang-ryeol in the past, he said 'Mongtaeju is a tavern' as soon as he saw me.
예전에서 지상렬 선배님 만났을 때 처음 보자마자 '몽타주가 주막이야'.
He said that to me, but even though I look like this, I hardly drink alcohol.
저한테 그렇게 했던 적이 있는데 생긴 건 이렇게 생겼어도 술을 거의 안 마시거든요.
What are you looking for? Now?
뭘 찾아요? 지금?
No, no
아니요 아니요
It's just a story I had.
그냥 그렇게 했던 얘기예요.
Yes
네
No, so now, Mr. Lee Soon-bong sent a story that he drank the ginseng liquor he had at home. Do you have any brew liquor at home?
아니 그러니까, 지금 이순봉씨께서 보내주신 사연이 집에 인삼주 담가 놓은 걸 먹었다고 얘기를 하잖아요. 혹시 집에 술 같은 거 담가 놓고 이러진 않죠?
No, I don't really brew liquor like that, I'm not that old and I don't really like alcohol.
네 저는 담금주를 막 담그고 그러지는 않습니다 나이도 나이고 술을 그렇게 좋아하지도 않아가지고.
When I go to the countryside, my father has quite a lot of liquor that has been brewed for about 30 years, about 60 bottles, but my father doesn't drink either.
저는 이제 시골에 가면 아버지가 담가 놓은 지 한 30년 된 술들이 꽤 많거든요 한 60병 있는데 아버지도 술을 안 드세요.
Why does he brew it?
왜 담그시는 거죠?
For decoration
관상용
Ah
아
But there was a similar incident, you know, snake liquor. A next-door neighbor caught a venomous snake and brewed it, and someone drank it.
근데 비슷한 사건이 있었는데, 이제 그 뱀주라 그러죠. 독사를 잡아다가 넣고 담아놨는데, 그걸 누가 이제 먹은 거죠.
Who drank it?
누가 드셨죠
This type of liquor needs to be aged for the venom to dissipate. However, the son couldn’t resist and drank it prematurely, then refilled the container with soju.
이제 옆집 아저씨가 그거를 담가 놨는데, 아들이 이제 그거를 먹고 한 2~3일 정도 밖에 안 된 소주를 부어 놓은 거죠.
The venom remained potent, and not long after, those who drank the liquor experienced hair loss and their teeth fell out.
그리고 이제 똑같이 친구분들이 아버지랑 같이 가서 그 뱀이 있는 술을 먹고, 이빨 다 빠지고, 머리 다 빠지고, 그랬던 게 실제로 있었어요
It's exactly the same situation as this story.
딱 이 사연과 같은 상황이네요.
Similar situation.
비슷한 상황이죠.
Yes
네
I'm sure you've given this a lot of thought, but if I were in your shoes, I would buy ginseng liquor on the internet and fill it up again.
생각을 다 해보셨겠지만, 저 같으면 인터넷에서 구매를 해서 다시 인삼주를 채워 놓는다.
That's what I'm thinking.
저는 그런 생각을 하고 있습니다.
What do you think?
어떻습니까?
From the wife's point of view, what would you do if your husband drank it all?
와이프 입장에서 남편이 다 먹었어 어떻게 하시겠습니까?
I would buy another liquor if it were me
다른 술을 사겠어요 저 같으면
No. I just took this liquor without knowing it for the holiday.
아니. 나는 모르고 그냥 이 술을 갖고 간 거지 명절 때.
But this is just plain water. Wow, our son got a job. Let's get together this time. Let's get together.
근데 이게 그냥 맹물인 거죠. 와 우리 아들 취업했잖아. 이번에 모여봐. 모여봐.
Ah let's eat, let's eat
아 먹자 먹자
I brewed it. Oh, it's plain water. What are you going to do?
내가 담가 놨어. 어 맹물이네. 어떻게 하시겠습니까?
I have to find it. Now search.
찾아야죠. 이제 수색.
Are you going to search?
수색을 한다고요?
Who is it? Who drank this?
누구야? 이거 마신사람?
Isn't it just the husband?
남편밖에 없지 않을까요?
Honey, come out.
여보 나와봐.
No, you're too kind now.
아니 너무 지금 착해.
He doesn't even come out when he says he will.
나온다고 나오지도 않을 뿐더러.
Ah, isn't it just a happening among family?
아 뭐 가족끼리 있는 해프닝이지 않을까요?
Hmm. Is that so?
음. 그래요?
Yes.
네.
I mean, my husband is a married man now. If ginseng liquor is expensive when I search the internet, I might not be able to afford it. If I worry about that, I have to break the bottle.
저는 뭐 남편이 지금 유부남이다 보니까. 인터넷 검색했을 때 인삼주가 좀 비싸다 그러면, 못 살 수도 있는 부분이니까. 그것까지 고민을 한다면 병을 깨야죠.
You're violent.
폭력적이시네요.
No, it's not violent.
아니 폭력적인 게 아니라.
No, it's a very pleasant thing and all the relatives are gathered, but if there's plain water in the ginseng liquor, wouldn't it be obvious what you did?
아니 굉장히 기분 좋은 일이고 친척끼리 다 모였는데 인삼주에 맹물 들어가 있으면 본인이 한 게 다 티가 나지 않습니까?
So I break it before that.
그래서 그 전에 이거를 깬다.
Destruction of evidence?
증거인멸?
'What should I do? I spilled it.' It seems like a good way to make an excuse.
'어떻게 하냐? 흘려버렸다' 이렇게 변명하면 좋은 방법인 것 같네요.
Is it good?
좋다고요?
Yes
네
You said it was violent earlier
폭력적이라고 하더니 좀 전에
I don't break this bottle with a scream, I break it with a surprise
저는 이 병을 으악 하고 깨버리는 게 아니라 어이쿠 하고 깨버리는 거죠
Yes, it's broken with a surprise. 'Honey, what should I do, it's like this.' You have to say. If you take plain water thinking 'It'll be fine.', it's a disaster.
네 어이쿠 툭 깨진 거죠. '여보 이거 어떡해 이렇게 됐어.' 라고 해야지. '그냥 잘 되겠지.' 하고 맹물 갖고 가는 순간 사단 납니다.
That's right, but both seem to get hit. I think I'll get hit if I just take it. I think I'll get hit if I break it.
그래요 근데 둘 다 등짝을 맞을 것 같은데요. 그냥 가져가도 한 대 맞을 것 같고. 깨도 한 대 맞을 것 같고.
Getting hit in front of relatives and getting hit here is different.
친척들 앞에서 맞는 거랑 여기서 맞는 거랑은 다르죠.
Is that so?
그런가요
Because now, the son got a job, that's the most important thing.
왜냐면 이제 그 아들이 취업을 했기 때문에 그게 제일 중요한데.
You might hear, ‘Your dad has messed up again.’ Isn’t it a holiday that you meet after a long time? I’m going to spin it into a bit of a self-made drama.
'니네 아빠가 또 초친다' 이런 얘기를 들을 수 있다 보니까. 오랜만에 만나는 명절 아니겠습니까? 저는 약간 자작극으로 돌려가지고.
Then if the wife feels a little better, she can ask 'Are you hurt?' up to that point
그러면 이제 와이프가 좀 기분이 좀 좋으면 '다친 데는 없어?' 거기까지 물어볼 수는 있지만
If she doesn't even ask that, it's just inevitable.
거기까지도 안 물어보면 아 그냥 어쩔 수 없는 거죠.
You have to move on like this.
이렇게 넘어가야죠.
I see, then Yong-guk's point.
그렇군요 그럼 용국이의 일침.
This is why fights break out when you drink like this on holidays.
명절 때 술을 이렇게 먹으면 이래서 싸움 나오는 겁니다.
Hmm
음
You don't understand, do you?
이해 안 되시죠?
Yes.
네.
I don't understand.
이해가 안 돼요.
Well, that's what it is.
일단 뭐 그렇다는 겁니다.
Yes
네
Let's move on, just yes and move on. If we keep doing this, there will be a story that fits our Luda.
넘어가시죠 그냥 네 넘어가시고. 이러다 보면 우리 루다씨 한테 맞는 사연이 하나가 올 거예요.
But there's a comment saying 'Isn't it better to just be honest?'
근데 댓글에 '그냥 그럴 바에는 그냥 솔직하게 말하는 게 낫지 않냐?'라는 댓글이 있거든요.
I think so too, just honestly say 'I drank it.'
저도 그렇게 생각해요 그냥 솔직하게 '내가 마셨어.'
'I'm sorry.' Isn't that better?
'죄송해요.' 이렇게 하는 게 낫지 않을까요
Now, that's a comment thrown because we don't know the personality of Mr. Soon-bong's wife.
이제 그거는 이제 그 순봉 씨의 와이프의 성격을 모르기 때문에 그렇게 던진 얘기죠.
Do you think he hasn't thought, "I can just be honest and tell my wife?
그 생각을 안 해봤겠습니까? 솔직하게 얘기하면 될 거라는 생각을 안 해봤겠어?
That's why he sent you the story, isn't it? 'Nobody knows the personality.' That's the point.
그러니까 사연을 보낸 거 아니겠습니까? '성격은 아무도 모른다.' 그게 포인트입니다.
I see
그렇군요
Yes, let's go to the next story
네 다음 사연 가시죠
Mr. 'Very Nice' sent a story, he's a man.
'아주나이스'님께서 남자분이 보내주신 사연인데요.
I'm a dieter, so I only drink cafe latte instead of lunch.
저는 소식자라 점심에 밥 대신 카페라떼만 먹습니다.
But I don't know any of the fun stories shared during lunch.
그런데 밥 먹을 때 나눈 재밌는 얘기 전 하나도 모르고요.
I can't follow when they go to buy coffee after eating.
밥 먹고 커피 사러 갈 때는 전 못 따라갑니다 .
Because I've already had coffee.
왜냐하면 전 이미 커피를 먹었으니까요.
So I'm gradually being ostracized, and this is subtly stressful.
그러다 보니 점점 소외되고있는데 이게 은근 스트레스입니다.
Even if I don't eat, can I follow the restaurant with a cafe latte? Would that be more strange? He sent it.
밥을 안먹더라도 카페라떼를 들고 식당 따라가도 될까요 그게 더 이상할까요? 라고 보내주셨어요.
You're not being ostracized, you were alone from the beginning. That's how I see it.
소외되고 있는 게 아니라 처음부터 혼자였다. 그렇게 봅니다
Hmm
음
When someone keeps walking around with a coffee while others are eating, no one cares if that person is a dieter or something. They just think, ‘Is he out of money?
밥 먹을 때 누군가가 자꾸 커피를 들고 돌아다녀. 그러면 이제 그 사람이 뭐 소식자인지 이런 거 관심 없고, '돈이 없나?'
What? What is that?
뭐야? 그게 뭐에요?
You can think like that.
그렇게 생각할 수 있다고요.
How do you know if there's latte, plain water, or green tea in it?
그 안에 라떼가 들었는지 맹물이 들었는지 녹차가 들었는지 어떻게 아냐고?
Who thinks like that?
그런 생각을 누가 해요?
Hmm. Then what do you think?
음. 그럼 어떻게 생각하시겠습니까?
He's carrying a tumbler, so he must be eating something.
그 텀블러 들고 다니니까 뭔가를 먹고 있나 보다.
Tumbler, no, I believe the listener who sent in the story is a man.
텀블러, 아닙니다 제가 봤을 땐 남자분 아니겠습니까?
Men don't use Tumblr well.
텀블러 은근히 많이 안 들어요.
Then just a paper cup?
그러면 그냥 종이컵?
No, not a paper cup, but a disposable cup from the cafe.
아니 종이컵이 아니라 그 카페에서 주는 일회용 컵.
Well, you usually see the contents.
어 그럼 보통 내용물이 보이잖아요.
If there's something hot outside, can't you see the inside well?
밖에 뜨거운 거 이렇게 있으면 안이 잘 안 보이지 않나요?
But do you think he's going to put plain water in there and drink green tea?
아 근데 거기에 맹물을 넣고 녹차를 먹을 거라고 생각한다?
No, I mean, people might not think it's expensive.
아니 그니까 비싼 거라고 생각을 안 할 수 있다는 거죠.
Every time I eat, he always carries that around
밥을 먹을 때마다 항상 쟤는 저걸 들고 다녀
Hmm
음
Do you think 'Is he having financial difficulties?'
'가정 형편이 어려운가?' 이런 생각을 한다고요?
Whether he's financially difficult or what he's done with his money.
가정 형편이 어렵든 자기가 뭐 돈을 딴 데 뭐 어떻게 해놨든.
When I see it, it doesn't look good.
봤을 때 모습이 그렇게 보기 좋지 않은데.
If he didn't explain that he's a dieter, people wouldn't know, right?
소식자인 건 자기가 설명을 안 했으면 사람들이 모를 수가 있잖아요.
That's right. That's true.
그렇죠. 그렇긴하죠.
So people might find it a little difficult to start a conversation.
그러다 보니까 사람들이 은근히 이제 말 붙이기가 좀 어렵겠죠.
'He seems to have some story.'
'쟤는 무슨 사연이 있나 보다.'
But 'Ppaceyong' said, 'These days, coffee is more expensive than lunch.'
근데 '빠쁘용' 님께서, '요즘 커피가 밥보다 비싸요.' 라고 말해주셨어요.
It's been expensive for a long time.
비싼 지는 오래됐죠.
We eat cheaper things more. You know.
싼 걸 더 많이 먹습니다. 알잖아요.
'Ah-ah'(Iced Americano)
'아아'(아이스 아메리카노)
Yes
네
Usually, the coffee price range that our store staff drink a lot is 2,000 won
보통 우리 그 가게 쪽에 직원분들이 많이 드시는 커피 가격대가 2천 원이에요
'Ah-ah' 2,000 won
'아아' 2천 원
'Ah-ah' is 2,000 won, and if you discount it, it's 1,800 won
'아아'가 2천 원이고, 할인하면 1800원입니다
Hmm.
음.
Of course, there are expensive places, but you won't carry around what's in expensive places, will you?
아 물론 비싼 데 있지 근데 비싼 데 있는 걸 갖고 다니진 않을 거 아닙니까
So I have to eat with people and listen to fun stories, but since I don't eat, I feel like I'm being ostracized.
그래서 사람들과 같이 밥도 먹고 재밌는 얘기도 들어야 되는데, 나는 밥을 안 먹다 보니까, 이렇게 소외되는 거 같다.
The most important thing is that this is all part of social life.
가장 중요한 건 이게 다 사회생활의 기본이라는 거죠.
Eating and mingling with people and drinking coffee,
밥을 먹고 사람들과 어울려서 커피를 마시고,
This is all part of social life
이게 다 사회생활의 일부다
You have to go like that unconditionally
무조건 그렇게 가죠
Then he'll have to follow the restaurant with a cafe latte. Then
그러면 카페라떼 하나 들고 식당을 따라가야겠네요. 그러면
No, he has to go and eat something, even if he pretend to eat.
아니 가서 뭐라도 먹어야지 먹는 척이라도.
Even if he pretend to eat? Because It's kind of awkward to bring a paper cup.
먹는 척이라도? 종이컵 가지고 가는 건 좀 그러니까
It looks like he only has this property.
너무 전 재산이 이거밖에 없는 것처럼 보이잖아.
If he brought a cafe latte.
카페라떼 하나 들고 왔으면.
So it's not that he only has that property, but I agree that it's part of social life. This is totally part of social life.
그러니까 전 재산이 그것만 있는 게 아니라 사회생활의 일부라는 거에 공감을 해요. 이거 완전 사회생활의 일부죠.
No, if he's the boss, he can do this
아니 자기가 사장이면 이렇게 해도 된다니까
If he's the boss, thank you.
사장이면 땡큐겠는데.
If he's the boss, it doesn't matter at all, but he keeps feeling ostracized.
전혀 상관이 없는데 자꾸 소외되는 걸 느낀다잖아요.
When he go to the coffee shop again, 'I have coffee, so it's awkward to go.' So
다시 커피숍을 갈 때 '나는 커피가 있으니까 가는 게 눈치가 보인다' 그러니까.
If he’s not going to be in social life for just a day or two, he has to adapt to it
이거는 이제 앞으로 사회생활 뭐 하루 이틀 하고 그만둘 거 아니면, 본인이 거기에 맞춰 가야죠.
That's right. I agree
그렇죠. 공감입니다
That's how you know what people are talking about.
그래야 이제 그 사람들이 어떤 얘기를 하는지 아는 거죠.
If I'm unique and I'm left out, it's not really special, it's ostracized.
내가 특이하다 그래서 내가 빠지면, 말 그대로 진짜 특별한 게 아니라 소외되는 겁니다.
I think so.
전 그렇다고 봐요.
I see, Park In-kyu said, 'In conclusion, Yong-guk doesn't get along well with Luda. Keke.'
그렇군요 박인규 님께서 '결론은 영국이 형이랑 루다는 잘 안 맞네요 크크.' 라고 보내주셨어요.
I'll take it as my fault for now
일단 뭐 제 잘못으로 하겠습니다
No, what's wrong? Then 'Yong-guk's point.'
아니 뭐 잘못이 있나요. 그러면 '용국이의 일침.'
The fun story shared while eating is most likely to be his gossip.
밥 먹을 때 나눈 재밌는 얘기는 이 분의 뒷담화일 확률이 제일 많습니다.
"Why does he only drink coffee?"
쟤는 왜 커피만 마셔
Yes, I understand. Let's move on.
네 알겠습니다. 넘어가시죠.
Next story
다음 사연
'Yongsang' sent it. She's a woman.
얼굴이 '용상' 님께서 보내주셨는데요. 여자분이십니다.
I have a complex about my long face. So when I take a picture, I use a filter that makes my face look short.
저는 긴 얼굴이 콤플렉스입니다. 그래서 사진 찍을 때면 얼굴이 짧게 나오는 필터를 쓰는데요.
Oh
오
When I match my face, the faces of the people next to me are excessively reduced, so I don't take pictures with other people as much as possible.
얼굴을 맞추면 옆 사람들이 얼굴이 과하게 줄여져서, 웬만하면 다른 사람들이랑 같이 사진을 안 찍어요.
But my friends are upset that I don't take any pictures with them and only post selfies and background pictures.
그런데 친구들이 왜 자기들이랑은 사진을 하나도 안 찍고 셀카랑 배경 사진만 올리냐며 서운해합니다.
Should I tell them honestly in this case?
이럴 땐 솔직히 말해야 될까요?
I just found out that there's a filter like this
저는 이런 필터가 있는지를 처음 알았어요
There's a filter that makes your face look short
얼굴이 짧게 나오는 필터가 있구나
These days, you can adjust everything, almost anything.
요즘은 그냥 뭐 다 조절할 수 있어요 웬만한 건.
There are a lot of fake faces.
가짜 얼굴들이 많죠.
Yes, you can just create new ones. Probably.
네 그냥 새롭게 만들 수가 있죠. 아무래도.
Right
그렇죠
Because of that, I think her friends are deliberately talking about it.
그것 때문에 이제 친구들이 저는 친구들이 일부러 알고 하는 얘기인 것 같습니다.
Wrong!
땡!
Why do you think friends wouldn't know?
왜 친구들이 모를 것 같아요.
Can I ask a question?
질문 있어요.
Can you socialize?
사회생활 가능하세요?
I go alone. I'm a self-employed person, aren't I?
저는 혼자 다니잖아요. 저는 자영업자 아니겠습니까.
Of course, but we're comedians, so we talk. You have a long face, very long.
물론 근데 저희는 또 개그맨 생활이라서 얘기해요. 너 얼굴 길어 많이 길어 얘기합니다.
Just open it.
그냥 오픈해서.
Here are ordinary office workers. And do friends not know this at all?
여기는 일반적인 직장인이잖아. 그리고 친구들이 이걸 아예 모를까?
Wouldn't they know I'm using my filter? They all know.
제 필터 쓰는 걸 모를까. 다 알죠.
But these days, there's no one who doesn't use a filter.
근데 요즘은 필터를 안 쓰는 사람이 없어요.
So.
그러니까.
No one.
없어요.
You roughly know what kind of filter it is. At first, there was Snow or something, right?
어떤 필터인지 대충 알잖아요. 제일 처음에 스노우인가 뭐 그거 있지 않습니까.
Right
그렇죠
We use that basically and use various things, but for some reason, they have nothing to say to her.
그런 것도 기본적으로 쓰고 여러 가지를 쓰는데, 아 쟤한테 그냥 왠지 할 말이 없으니까.
"Hey, why don’t you take a picture with us?” They just said it out of courtesy,
'야 우리랑 같이 사진 왜 안 찍어?' 같이 찍어 알면서 던진 말인데,
I think this person is paying too much attention here. That's what I think.
이 사연자분께서 괜히 여기 신경을 많이 쓰신 것 같다. 저는 그렇게 생각을 합니다.
The conclusion is that friends know everything.
결론은 친구들이 다 알고 한 말이다.
Yes, so you don't have to worry at all.
네 그렇기 때문에 전혀 뭐 신경을 안 써도 되고.
Ignore it
무시해라
Yes, but if it's comfortable to talk honestly, you can talk.
네 그거를 근데 솔직하게 얘기하는 부분이 편할 거면 얘기해도 돼요.
If you're upset again, your friends will think, "She's not telling us on purpose because of that."
괜히 또 꿍하고 있으면, 쟤 또 저런 것 때문에 일부러 얘기 안 하고 있잖아.
Instead of being secretive, talk honestly and ignore it as much as possible.
꿍할 바엔 솔직하게 얘기하고 웬만하면 그냥 무시해라.
What will you do?
어떻게 하시겠습니까?
If my face is a bit long, let's take a picture with friends. If we take it together, it shrinks and looks weird.
내가 만약에 얼굴이 좀 긴데, 친구들을 잡고 찍자 그래. 같이 찍으면 같이 줄어들어 이상하게 나와.
What would you say if your friends asked why you don't take pictures?
그 친구들이 사진 왜 안 찍냐고 물어봐? 뭐라고 얘기하시겠어요?
If it were me, I would just take it. What's wrong with your friend's face looking like this?
저라면 그냥 찍어요. 친구 얼굴 이렇게 나와 어쩌라고.
Oh, your friend's face looks like this? As long as you look pretty?
아 친구 얼굴 이렇게 나온다고? 자기만 예쁘게 나오면 된다고?
So what, I look good in the picture.
어쩌라고, 난 예쁘게 나와 이러면서.
This is the answer because you see a good picture of yourself.
이게 정답이긴 합니다 솔직하게 자기가 잘 나온 사진이다 보니까.
Right, right
그렇죠 그렇죠
First, take it. Like Luda said, just take a picture and your friend's face
일단 찍으세요 우리 루디 말처럼 그냥 찍고 친구 얼굴이
Even if it becomes a pizza, as long as you look pretty. Please take it quickly.
뭐 피자가 되는 말도 자기만 예쁘게 나오면 되니까. 일단 빨리 찍어주세요.
After taking it, say, "Hey, is your face a pizza?"
찍고 나서 야 너 얼굴 피자냐 이렇게 해라.
Let's do that. It doesn't seem like a good solution, but let's do that for now.
그렇게 하자 뭐 좋은 해결책은 아닌 것 같은데, 일단 그렇게 하라고 합니다.
'Yong-guk's point'
'용국의 일침'
Is it very long?
많이 긴가요?
?
?
Why? No, play the xylophone a little.
왜요? 아니 실로폰을 좀 해줘요.
Is it very long? What should I hit?
많이 긴가요? 뭐 뭐 쳐야지.
I'm a little curious too.
저도 조금 궁금하네요.
Yes, I just asked.
네 여쭤본 겁니다.
Yes, we're starting Part 4
네 4부 시작합니다
'He said' sent 'Devil Duo'.
'얘가 말한대' 님께서요 '악마 2인조' 라고 보내주셨어요.
We're talking, right? Probably.
저희 말하는 거겠죠? 아무래도.
There are only two of us, so it must be us
둘 밖에 없으니까 저희겠죠
Oh, come on.
아이 그럴리가요.
'BFP' said, 'Wow, the DJ and the guest are the worst. Kekeke.'
'비피피' 님께서 '와 진짜 디제이랑 게스트가 제일 나빠 크크크'.
'Jeon Byung-gok' said, 'Today's broadcast is overall precarious.'
'전병곡' 님께서 '오늘 전체적으로 방송이 아슬아슬하네요' 라고.
Hey, what's precarious about this?
에이 이게 뭐 아슬아슬합니까.
With this much.
이 정도 가지고.
Is it okay?
괜찮죠?
I'm doing very well normally.
아주 뭐 노멀하게 잘 가고 있습니다.
It's normal. It's normal.
노멀합니다. 노멀합니다.
'An Kyung-seon', this person is a man
'안경선' 님께서, 이 분은 남자분이세요
He sent a story.
사연을 보내주셨는데.
I'm preparing for a job. My college senior asked me to help with some work, so I helped a few times to put it in my portfolio.
취업 준비 중입니다. 대학 선배가 일 좀 도와 달래서 포트폴리오에 넣을 겸 일을 몇 번 도와줬는데요.
Now, he calls me anytime as if he thinks of me as an employee.
이제 절 직원으로 생각하는지 아무 때나 절 불러댑니다.
Without paying me. He says, "I'm helping you to get a job well," and I can't believe it.
돈도 안 주면서. 너 취업 잘하라고 내가 도와주는 거야 라고 하는데 어이가 없습니다.
I think I'll be working in the same industry, is there a way to end it nicely?
동종업계에서 일하게 될 것 같은데 좋게 마무리하는 방법 없을까요.
First of all, what I feel is that if he doesn't pay him now, he won't pay him even if sender do harder work in the future.
일단은 제가 느끼는 건 지금 돈을 안 주는 사람이면, 앞으로 더 힘든 일을 해도 돈을 줄 일은 없다.
If he pays a lot, he will give him 10,000 won.
많이 주면 한 만 원 주겠다.
He won't pay him even if sender help him more.
더 도와줘 봤자 돈은 안 준다.
And you can just not answer the phone.
네 그리고 전화를 그냥 안 받으면 되는 거고요.
There is a limit to what you can do without any reward.
어떤 대가 없이 해주는 일은 한계가 있고.
Hmm..
음..
He's used to it and thinks it's natural.
그게 습관이 되어 있고 당연한 줄 안다.
Hmm, I think so
음 그런 것 같아요
The senior is just a senior when you're in school,
선배는 학교 다닐 때는 선배인 거고,
Because he becomes just an acquaintance when you need him, you don't need to be swayed too much.
내가 필요할 때는 그냥 아는 지인이 되기 때문에, 너무 휘둘릴 필요가 없다.
That's what I think.
그렇게 생각을 합니다.
But the problem is that he thinks he'll be working in the same industry, so he wants to end it nicely.
근데 이게 고민하시는 게 동종업계에서 일하게 될 것 같아서 좋게 마무리하고 싶다.
sender hasn't got a job yet. he could still fail.
취직 안 했잖아. 아직 떨어질 수도 있잖아.
Right, it might not be the same industry.
그렇죠 동종업계가 안 될 수도 있으니까.
That's something to think about then. Right?
그건 그때 생각하면 되는 거고. 그렇잖아요.
Right?
그렇죠?
Yes
네
You can worry about that once you get a job.
아니 동종업계는 자기가 붙은 다음에 그 다음에 하는 거고,
You don't need to think about the worries that won't come now,
다가오지 않을 고민을 갖고 와서 지금 생각할 필요는 없는 거고,
Aren't you uncomfortable with the current situation?
지금 상황에 불편하지 않습니까?
Right
그렇죠
And from the sender's story, it seems like you're quite skilled.
그리고 사연자님께서 남겨주신 게 실력이 어느 정도 되시는 것 같은데.
Then the feeling will change again when the time comes.
그럼 그때 되면 또 느낌이 또 달라져요.
So don't stress about bringing the situation ahead now,
그러니까 그 앞 상황을 갖고 와서 지금 스트레스 받지 마시고,
Now, even though this senior is looking for you, aren't you uncomfortable?
지금 그렇게 뭐 이 선배가 나를 찾긴 하지만 내가 불편하지 않습니까.
Then you can block it,
그러면은 뭐 차단할 수도 있는 거고,
'I don't answer', so you don't need to be sorry,
저는 안 받는다 그래서 미안할 필요 없는 거고,
If you use someone, you have to pay a price.
사람을 갖다 썼으면 대가를 지불해야 당연한 거다.
Right.
그렇죠.
That's why you don't get dragged to the Ministry of Employment and Labor. There's that.
그래야 고용노동부에 안 끌려간다. 그런 게 있습니다.
So 'even though I think I'll be working in the same industry, I haven't yet.' Just ignore it?
그럼 동종업계에 일하게 될 것 같은 거지만 아직 안 하니까. 그냥 씹어라?
Right.
그렇죠.
You mean that.
이 말씀이신 거죠.
That's the best. Even if you make an excuse, you know. While saying just one last time,
그게 가장 좋아요 변명을 대봤자 알았어. 마지막 한 번만 한 번만 하면서,
"Hey, I'm taking care of you on purpose." Isn't this a non-abuse of power?
야 너 내가 다 일부러 챙겨주는 거야. 이렇게 또 갑질이 아닌 갑질을 하지 않습니까?
Hmm
음
You only get stressed and it's not a talent donation, and it's not once or twice, so it's uncomfortable.
스트레스만 받고 가서 재능 기부도 아니고, 한두 번도 아니다 보니까 불편하죠.
So now that you've done enough, think about the future,
그래서 이제 할 만큼 하셨으니까, 그 앞으로의 일은 나중에 생각하시고,
Now you can just block it.
지금은 그냥 차단해도 된다.
In the comments, 'Another person like that is already rumored.'
댓글에 '또 그런 사람은 이미 소문이 다 나 있다.'
Where is the rumor?
어디에 소문이 났다고요?
In the same industry, a person who doesn't pay and uses people
그 동종업계에 그렇게 돈을 안 주고 사람을 부려먹는 사람은
The rumor is already out, a comment came up
이미 다 소문이 나 있다 이렇게 댓글이 올라왔어요
This person seems like someone who doesn't work at a company
이 분 회사 안 다니시는 분 같은데
Huh?
어?
You're not working, are you?
안 다니시잖아요?
No, how narrow is the industry that the rumor is out? Now, if a company says 'Assistant manager. Kim', do you know?
아니 업계가 얼마나 좁길래 소문이 나? 지금 무슨 기업이 무슨 '김대리'라고 하면 알아?
You don't know.
모르잖아요.
So it's a portfolio. It's not a company.
그래 포트폴리오니까. 회사는 아닌 거겠죠.
It's just a throwaway comment
그냥 던지는 얘기예요
So you don't have to find meaning in everything. Just throw it away.
그러니까 모든 거에 의미를 안 구해야 됩니다. 그냥 막 던집니다.
There are a lot of people like that. You don't have to worry too much.
그런 사람들이 많다 보니까. 너무 신경 안 쓰셔도 되고.
So what's the way to end it nicely?
그래서 좋게 마무리하는 방법은?
Now just block it.
지금 일단 그냥 차단.
Block
차단
Yes.
네.
If I'm good, it's good.
내가 좋으면 좋은 거다.
Right
그렇죠
Yes, that's better.
네 그게 낫죠.
'Yong-guk's point'
'용국이의 일침'
I think I should end it badly.
나쁘게 마무리해야 될 것 같습니다.
You should block and not see each other, and you should go your separate ways.
차단하고 서로 안 보는 거고 남남으로 가야죠.
That's not bad.
나쁘지 않습니다.
Right. The best way to end it is if I'm good, it's good.
그렇죠. 제일 좋게 마무리하는 건 내가 좋으면 좋은 겁니다.
Right, if I'm good, it's good.
그렇죠 내가 좋으면 좋은 거죠
'Kim Sung-hee' sent it as 'gender unknown'.
'김성희' 님께서 '성별 미상'으로 보내주셨어요.
I like gelato, so I often go to the gelato shop.
젤라또를 좋아해서 젤라또 가게 자주 가는데요.
I'm the one who buys and eats gelato,
젤라또 사 먹는 사람은 저인데,
The employee keeps smiling at my friend.
직원이 자꾸 제 친구에게 웃어줍니다.
They don't talk to each other, but I'm jealous.
둘이 서로 말은 안 하는데 질투나요.
Is there a way to get the employee's attention?
직원의 시선을 저에게 가져올 방법 없나요?
What was this story about?
무슨 사연이었나 이게.
Gelato?
'젤라또?
Do people these days eat gelato well?
요즘 사람들 젤라또를 잘 먹나요?
I like it
저는 좋아해요
Really?
그래요?
But it's expensive, so I don't eat it often.
근데 비싸가지고 잘 안 먹거든요.
What exactly is gelato? I don't know exactly.
젤라또가 정확하게 뭐예요? 정확하게 몰라가지고.
Isn't it Turkish ice cream? Gelato?
터키 아이스크림 아닌가요? 젤라또가?
Ah
아
There's that chewy ice cream.
그 쫄깃쫄깃한 아이스크림 있잖아요.
Is that gelato?
그게 젤라또예요?
Yes, I guess so
네 맞을걸요
It's called Italian ice cream.
이탈리아 아이스크림이라고.
It's Italian ice cream.
이탈리아 아이스크림이군요.
I got it, they wrote it here again because I couldn't recognize it.
알았어 그걸 또 썼어 여기다가 또 못 알아본다고.
Italian ice cream
이탈리아 아이스크림
I don't even eat Korean ice cream, so what Italian ice cream do I eat?
한국 아이스크림도 안 먹는데 무슨 이탈리아 아이스크림을 먹고 있어. 지금.
But now the employee smiles at his friend.
근데 이제 직원분이 자기 친구한테 웃어준다.
There must be a reason.
이유가 있겠죠.
Right, because he looks funny.
그렇죠 웃기게 생겼다든가.
He looks funny, so he laughs.
웃기게 생겨서 웃는 것이다.
That could be the case.
그럴 수도 있죠.
When we do comedy, the most comfortable thing is,
우리가 이제 코미디 할 때 가장 편한 게 뭐냐면,
Makeup.
분장입니다.
It bursts as soon as it appears.
등장하면서 터져요.
But you know that, whether it's funny or not,
근데 그거 알잖아요 이게 웃겨서 웃는 건지,
Or if he laughs strangely.
아니면 묘하게 웃는 건지.
That's just a polite thing to say
그러니까 이분한테 그냥 기분 좋게 하려고 하는 얘기고
she won't look at him
이분한테 시선이 안 가겠죠
He pays here and gets the goods here, but she's laughing over there.
계산을 여기서 하고 물건을 여기서 하는데 저길 보고 웃고 있다.
Then there's no need to talk.
그러면 얘기할 필요가 없는 거잖아.
Right. Here's the person who pays the money, and that person doesn't eat,
그렇잖아요. 여기가 돈을 내는 사람인데 저 사람은 먹지도 않는데,
If she looks at his friend and laughs, he must not have talked.
쟤를 보고 웃고 있으면 말은 당연히 안 했겠죠.
So what, just at that moment,
그러니까 뭐 거기까지 딱 보는 순간,
This has to be acknowledged, right?
이거는 인정해야 되지 않나.
So is there a way to get the employee's attention?
그럼 직원의 시선을 가져올 수 있는 방법은 없을까요.
I don't think so.
없을 것 같습니다.
No. You have to keep asking.
없죠. 자꾸 뭘 물어봐야 될 거 아니야.
If you try to get attention, don't you just throw strange questions?
시선 가져온다고 이상한 질문 막 던지지 않습니까.
When does this come out? Isn't there a new product?
이거 언제 나오나요? 신제품 안 나오나요?
The employee is very annoyed.
직원분 엄청 귀찮아합니다.
That's the worst question.
최악이다 그런 질문.
He looks weird and keeps asking weird things.
쟤는 이상하게 생겼어 이상한 거 자꾸 물어봐.
I feel like this, so I have to go to another store now.
이런 느낌 나다 보니까 이거는 이제 다른 매장은 가야지.
It's hard at this store. The employee's gaze is fixed.
이 매장에선 힘들다. 직원 시선이 고정돼 있다 그런 거죠.
'Yong-guk's point'
'용국이의 일침'
Just eat gelato.
그냥 젤라또나 먹자.
That's neatly done. There's no point in worrying about that.
그게 제일 깔끔하지. 뭐 그거 신경 써서 결혼이 어딨어 지금.
If the person who is receiving my money doesn’t look at me, there's no answer. This is.
계산하는 사람도 안 쳐다보면 답이 없는 거예요. 이거는.
Right, why do you need to get the employee's attention? Right.
그래요 직원 시선을 굳이 가져서 뭐해요. 그렇죠.
It's not coming anyway.
어차피 오지도 않을 건데.
Look over there, that's what it is.
거기 보세요 이렇게 하는 거죠.
I found out for the first time today that it's Italian ice cream.
오늘 처음 알았네 이탈리아 아이스크림이라는 걸.
Me too. I didn't know it was Italian ice cream while I was eating it deliciously.
저도 그러네요. 맛있게 먹으면서 이탈리아 아이스크림인 줄은 몰랐어요.
Go to the supermarket. Eat Korean ice cream.
슈퍼 가세요 슈퍼. 한국 아이스크림 드세요.
I understand.
알겠습니다.
The fifth part of Luda's Ten has started.
루다의 텐 5부가 시작됐고요.
'One Knife' sent 'It's Luda's fifth part, haha'.
'원 나이프 님'께서 '이루다 5부다 크크' 라고 보내주셨어요.
It's the first fifth part in the history of Baeten.
배텐 역사상 최초 5부라고.
I didn't know. Is it the fifth part?
저는 몰랐습니다. 5부인지.
I will try to do up to ten parts later.
10부작까지 제가 한번 나중에 한번 해보도록 하겠습니다.
'Rootray' sent 'Let's love domestic ice cream. Is the ending real?'
'루트레이' 님께서 '국산 아이스크림 사랑합시다. 엔딩 실화냐?' 라고 보내주셨어요.
Since we can't point out the face. Let's eat domestic ice cream.
얼굴을 지적할 수는 없으니까. 국산 아이스크림 먹자.
'Go Dae-sung' sent 'It's a shame that it's over now that we've got the hang of it.'
'고대성' 님께서는 '이제 호흡 맞았는데 끝나서 아쉽다.' 라고 보내주셨어요.
Luda said, 'I'm very shy.' So, I think she was very surprised to see me.
루디가 '낯을 많이 가린다.' 그래가지고, 저를 보고 많이 놀란 것 같습니다.
From next time, I think I'll sit back and talk to you.
다음부터는 뒤돌아서 앉아서 얘기해 드릴 것 같아요.
I was surprised.
좀 놀랐어요.
The shortest fifth part
최고로 짧은 5부
If you have any concerns for 'Yonghan Counseling Center', please send them to the Monday bulletin board or,
'막 나가는 용한상담소' 고민 사연 있으신 분들은 월요일 게시판이나,
#1077 Short text 50 won, long text 100 won.
#1077 짧은 문자 50원 긴 문자 100원이 드는 문자로 보내주세요.
We will send a six-pack exchange coupon to those who have been introduced to the story.
사연 소개된 분들께는 선물 식스팩 교환권 보내드릴게요.
Thank you for your hard work today, Mr. Jung Yong-guk.
오늘도 정용국 씨 수고하셨고요.
Today is the first day of Luda's Ten, how was my radio broadcast today?
오늘 루다의 텐 첫날인데, 저의 진행 어떠셨나요?
Ah, it was fun. Yes, it was good.
아 재밌었습니다. 네 좋았어요.
Monday, September 25, 2023
2023년 9월 25일 월요일
I'm really proud to finish with the fifth part of Ten.
텐 5부작으로 마무리해서 정말 뿌듯합니다.
You've worked hard.
수고하셨습니다.
I'll finish Luda's Ten like this,
루다의 텐 이렇게 마무리하고,
I'll be back tomorrow.
저는 내일 다시 돌아오겠습니다.
Then I'll turn off the lights. Dream of Luda.
그럼 소등하겠습니다. 루다 꿈꾸세요.